{"data":[
	{
		"question":
			"The processes and activities involved in establishing, nurturing and sustaining a business enterprise is called what?",
		"answer": "Entrepreneurship"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Corporate entrepreneurship is a method by which individuals or group of individuals in association with a new or existing organization work together to create a product. TRUE / FALSE",
		"answer": "True"
	},
	{ "question": "TIC stands for", "answer": "Technology Incubation Centres" },
	{
		"question": "Examples of level of operations for NGOs can be",
		"answer": "Community-based, city-wide and national"
	},
	{
		"question": "A business association of two or more persons is known as",
		"answer": "Partnership"
	},
	{
		"question": "Companies which their names end with Limited are known as",
		"answer": "Private Limited Liability Company"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Corporate bonds issued by a company or government, secured by the company assets, specifying an obligation to return borrowed funds with interest is called what?",
		"answer": "Debenture Stocks"
	},
	{ "question": "When was CSR originated?", "answer": "1950s" },
	{
		"question":
			"Joseph Schumpeter, an Australian Economist said entrepreneurship is driven by what?",
		"answer": "Innovation"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A place where staffs are restricted from communicating with the managers and the company don't reward staffs for their creative effort encourages Intrapreneurship. TRUE / FALSE",
		"answer": "FALSE"
	},
	{
		"question": "Israel Kirzner describes an Entrepreneur as a ",
		"answer":
			"person who is at alert to market changes and has the ability of grabbing opportunities in the market."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The invention of new things that have value or something that doesn't exist before is called what?",
		"answer": "Creativity"
	},
	{
		"question": "What organization is charged with the protection of copyright?",
		"answer": "Nigerian Copyright Commission (NCC)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The agency in charge of registering patents and trademarks is called what?",
		"answer": "National Office for Technology Acquisition and Promotion (NOTAP)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Who founded FCMB - the first solely Nigeria owned marchant bank?",
		"answer": "Otunba Michael Olasubomi Balogun"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Any non-profit, voluntary citizens' group which is organized on a local or national level, task-oriented and driven by people with common interest is known as ",
		"answer": "Non-Governmental Organisation (NGO)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A stage when cash flow has stabilised and monthly financial statements might show profit is called",
		"answer": "Stabilisation stage - lasts one to two years"
	},
	{
		"question": "When was EFCC established?",
		"answer": "It was set up in 2003"
	},
	{
		"question": "When was ICPC established?",
		"answer": "In the year 2000"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the 3 reasons for Entrepreneurship",
		"answer": "Push factors, pull factors and supportive factors"
	},
	{
		"question": "Pull factors are referred to as what?",
		"answer":
			"Favourable events that encourage someone to venture into entrepreneurship such as good business environment, presence of partners, etc"
	},
	{
		"question": "PESTEL stands for",
		"answer":
			"Political, Economic, Social, Technological, Environmental and Legal"
	},
	{
		"question": "The full meaning of NDIC is",
		"answer": "Nigeria Deposit Insurance Commission"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the full meaning of SMART?",
		"answer": "Specific, Measureable, Attainable, Reliable and Time-bound"
	},
	{
		"question": "List two works eligible for copyright protection in Nigeria",
		"answer":
			"Literary works, artistic works, cinematograph film, sound recordings and broadcast."
	},
	{
		"question": "FIIRO stands for what?",
		"answer": "The Federal Institute of Industrial Research, Oshodi"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"\"The enterprise that does not innovate, inevitably ages and declines. And in a period of rapid change such as the present... the decline will be fast. \" Who made this statement?",
		"answer": "Drucker (1985)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"What are the stages to be followed to avoid poor feasibility study?",
		"answer":
			"Market study, Technical analysis, financial analysis and management"
	},
	{
		"question": "CACS stands for what?",
		"answer": "Commercial Agricultural Credit Scheme"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Which agency is in charge of ensuring that standard materials are produced by manufacturers for construction of buildings?",
		"answer": "Standard Organization of Nigeria"
	},
	{
		"question": "Entrepreneur was derived from a French word name what?",
		"answer": "Enterprendre - means to undertake / to start a business"
	},
	{
		"question": "List 7 skills of an Entrepreneur",
		"answer":
			"LIFORTS - Leadership, Integrity, Future-oriented, Originality, Risk Taking, Task-result oriented, Self-confidence"
	},
	{
		"question": "Push factors are referred to as what?",
		"answer":
			"Unpleasant life experiences and events, including SAPA, pay dissatisfaction, unemployment, etc "
	},
	{
		"question":
			"In what book did Jean-Baptiste Say (1767 -1832) define Entrepreneurs as economic agents who unites all means all means of production?",
		"answer":
			"A Treatise on Political Economy or The Production, Distribution and Consumption of Wealth (1803, 1971)"
	},
	{
		"question": "Who is the Father of Innovation?",
		"answer": "Joseph Aloi Schumpeter"
	},
	{
		"question": "RMRDC was founded when and commenced operations when?",
		"answer":
			"RMRDC was established by the Federal government through decree number 39 of 1987. It commenced operations in 1988"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A business partner who actively engage in daily operations of the business is known as ",
		"answer": "Active / Managing / Working partner"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The type of merger between firms in different stages of production operation but in the same industry, like car company purchasing tyre company is called",
		"answer": "Vertical Merger"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"When a buyer acquires more than 50% of a company, leading to a change of control. This process is called",
		"answer": "Buy-out"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A private equity that is provided to small, early-stage and emerging firms are known as",
		"answer": "Venture Capital"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is secondary packaging?",
		"answer":
			"It is the container which is discarded when the product is about to be used."
	},
	{
		"question": "Standard Organization of Nigeria was created in the year?",
		"answer": "1971"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is Interpreneurship?",
		"answer":
			"It is the practice of beginning and developing new ventures within the structure of an existing large organization."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The major contibutor to Psychological Entrepreneurship theory is",
		"answer":
			"David McClelland. His theory of entrepreneurship is based on personal characteristics and traits"
	},
	{
		"question": "The full meaning of IPR is",
		"answer": "Intellectual Property Right"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Valuable information which are kept secret by business owners are known as",
		"answer": "Trade Secrets"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The improvement of existing production processes that affects the environments is known as",
		"answer": "Eco-process Innovation"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"An enterprise formed to satisfy consumers through the production of goods/services is known as what?",
		"answer": "Business Venture"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A type of merger that occurs between firms that produce similar products or goods is called",
		"answer": "Horizontal Merger"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The process of earning profits by meetings customers' needs and making sure they are satisfied is known as",
		"answer": "Marketing"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the two types of packaging",
		"answer": "Primary and Secondary packaging"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the full meaning of EFCC?",
		"answer": "Economic and Financial Crimes Commission"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the full meaning of ICPC?",
		"answer": "Independent Corrupt Practices Commission"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The word Entrepreneurship was first used by who, when he was living where and in what year?",
		"answer":
			"Richard Cantillon, an Irish man in the early 18th century in France"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Individuals who attempt to predict and act upon change within markets is known as what?",
		"answer": "An Entrepreneur"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Entrepreneurs who drive social innovation and transformation in various fields including educaton, health, human rights, etc are called what?",
		"answer": "Social Entrepreneurs"
	},
	{
		"question": "Read more on Theories of Entrepreneurship from page 10 -18",
		"answer": "Open the manual or click the next button"
	},
	{
		"question": "The patents and design registration is governed by what?",
		"answer": "The Patents and Designs Act 1970, in Cap 344 LFN 1990"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A branch of law that grants authors the exclusive privilege to reproduce, distribute or display their creative works is called what?",
		"answer": "Copyright"
	},
	{
		"question": "Examples of level of orientation for NGOs can be: ",
		"answer":
			"charitable, service, participatory and empowering orientation (pg. 146)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"In what type of company is the shares open to the public for purchase?",
		"answer": "Public Limited Liability Company"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A situation whereby payments for a goods and services is deferred till a later date by the agreement of both the buyer and seller is called what?",
		"answer": "Trade Credit"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The first round of institutional ventire capital to fund growth is known as",
		"answer": "Series A round"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is primary packaging?",
		"answer": "It is the product's immediate container"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The surroundings within and outside in which the business operates is called what?",
		"answer": "Business Environment"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"S and W in SWOT analysis are used to examine what type of business environment",
		"answer": "Internal environments"
	},
	{
		"question": "The system of Trademark registration in Nigeria is governed by?",
		"answer": "the Trademarks Act 1965"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The trademarks, design and patent laws are administered by what ministry in Nigeria?",
		"answer": "Federal Ministry of Commerce and Industry"
	},
	{
		"question": "When and where did the industrial revolution take place?",
		"answer": "In the late 18th and 19th centuries, Britain"
	},
	{
		"question": "The Three Circle in family business are:",
		"answer": "The ownership, family and management circle"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Partners who losses and responsibilities are restricted to their different shares and do not take part in managing the business are called",
		"answer": "Limited partners"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The minimum number of people that constitutes a Cooperative Society is",
		"answer": "10"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the 4Ps of Marketing",
		"answer": "Product, Price, Promotion and Place"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Entrepreneurs who think newer, better and more economical ideas of business organization are called what?",
		"answer": "Innovative Entrepreneurs"
	},
	{
		"question": "Who is an Intrapreneur?",
		"answer":
			"An entrepreneur within an already established organization. He also chooses to use new combination of the organization's resources. In Intrapreneurship, the organization seeks to expand by exploring new opportunities using new combinations of the existing resources."
	},
	{
		"question": "Schumpeter described an Entrepreneur as a ",
		"answer": "An innovator and leader of firm."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"What industry was the most important starting point of industrialization in England?",
		"answer": "Textile industry"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The three stages of innovation recognized by Joseph Schumpeter are:",
		"answer": "invention, innovation and diffusion"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the types of business plans?",
		"answer":
			"Mini or short plans, working plans, presentation plans, electronic plans."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The type of plan that is used to operate the business is called ",
		"answer": "Working plan"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The type of buy-out that occurs as a result of loan defaults, with the company used as a collateral is called",
		"answer": "Leverage buy-out"
	},
	{ "question": "CACS was established when?", "answer": "April 2010" },
	{
		"question":
			"The persuasion of consumers to buy goods and services from your firms is called",
		"answer": "Selling"
	},
	{
		"question": "The three main kinds of trademarks are: ",
		"answer": "Service marks, collective marks and certification marks"
	},
	{
		"question": "The three major functions of NGO identified by Stromquist are: ",
		"answer":
			"Service delivery, educational provision and public policy advocacy"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A document that clarifies and expresses the respective intention of partners in a business is called",
		"answer": "Deed of Partnership"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A partner who share the profits of the business but not the losses is called",
		"answer": "Partner in profits"
	},
	{
		"question": "The term \"cooperative\" is derived from a Latin word called",
		"answer": "Co-operari - \"co\" means with and \"operari\" means to work"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A document that describes business goals, strategies and how to dolve potentials problems is known as",
		"answer": "Business Plan"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The type of business plan that is shown to investors or bankers is called",
		"answer": "Presentation plan"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A kind of short term loan or finance given to bank account owners is called",
		"answer": "Bank Overdraft"
	},
	{
		"question": "Bank of Industry was established when?",
		"answer": "October 2001 under Pres. Olusegun Obasanjo regime"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Entrepreneurs who are also referred to copy cats because they imitate innovative entrepreneurs are called what?",
		"answer": "Imitating Entrepreneurs"
	},
	{
		"question": "Who is the Father of Entrepreneurship",
		"answer": "Richard Cantillon (1680 - 1755)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The systematic application of creative ideas to explore market opportunities is known as",
		"answer": "Innovation"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The stage of recognizing an opportunity, analyzing the idea and mobilizing resources to start the business is known as",
		"answer": "Conceptual Stage"
	},
	{
		"question": "Describe the Start-up stage of a business",
		"answer":
			"A stage where the entrepreneurs' vision is tested. It usually lasts between a year and half and two years"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A purchase of one company by another in which no new company is formed is known as what?",
		"answer": "Acquisition"
	},
	{ "question": "NAFDAC was found in the year", "answer": "1992" },
	{
		"question": "The process of creation is known as what?",
		"answer": "Entrepreneurship"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Cantillon's economic system is based on three agents, which are:",
		"answer":
			"Landowners (Capitalists), Entrepreneurs (Arbitragers) and Labourer (Wageworkers)"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The use of signs and symbols to distinguish goods and services from others is called?",
		"answer": "Trademarks"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A document that forms the constitution of the company, shows the rules and regulations which govern the external relationship of a company is called",
		"answer": "Memorandum of Association"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The type of merger that occurs between firms that are totally unrelated is called",
		"answer": "Conglomerate Merger"
	},
	{
		"question": "Supportive factors are referred to as what?",
		"answer": "Culture, peer group, social condition, etc"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The two empirical ideas that establish Corporate Entrepreneurship are what?",
		"answer": "Strategic entrepreneurship and corporate venturing."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"In what year did the US Congress adopt the first Federal trademark law?",
		"answer": "1870"
	},
	{ "question": "Who founded Samsung group?", "answer": "Lee Byung-Chul" },
	{
		"question": "The number of people in a business partnership ranges from",
		"answer": "2-20 persons"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"An analysis carried out on a business idea that determines whether such business will thrive and be profitable is called what?",
		"answer": "Feasibility study"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A business organization whereby an established firm with a successful product licenses its trademark and method of doing business to other businesses in exchange for a fee and an ongoing royalty payment is called",
		"answer": "Franchising"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"When two firms from different but adjacent industries merge is called",
		"answer": "Concentric Merger"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The activities involved in designing and producing the container or wrapper for a product is called",
		"answer": "Packaging"
	},
	{
		"question": "CSR stands for what?",
		"answer": "Corporate Social Responsibility"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Entrepreneurs who create products based on a threat to their existence or are motivated due to some developments are known as what?",
		"answer": "Fabian Entrepreneurs"
	},
	{
		"question": "Frank Knight described an Entrepreneur as a ",
		"answer":
			"person able and prepared to undertake risks and bear the uncertainty of entrepreneurship. He simplified Cantillon's theory of entrepreneurship."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"O and T in SWOT analysis are used to examine what type of business environment",
		"answer": "External environments"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the full meaning of WIPO?",
		"answer": "World Intellectual Property Organisation"
	},
	{ "question": "FIIRO was established in what year?", "answer": "1956" },
	{
		"question":
			"The type of innovation whereby a unique invention that solves a particular problem is introduced to the market is known as",
		"answer": "Radical or Breakthrough innovation"
	},
	{
		"question": "The most common reason of a joint venture is to",
		"answer": "gain access to a foreign market"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A private financing whereby business owners give up part of their ownership to an external party is called",
		"answer": "Venture capital"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the full meaning of SWOT? ",
		"answer": "Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities and Threats"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The US Congress adopted both patent and copyright laws in what year?",
		"answer": "1790"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The legal document that describes the invention and grants property right to the inventor is called?",
		"answer": "Patent"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The event that aided the development of science and technology, use of machines and inanimate sources of power is known as what?",
		"answer": "The Industrial Revolution"
	},
	{
		"question": "What is the full meaning of RMRDC?",
		"answer": "Raw Materials Research and Development Council"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The introduction of new significantly improved products that affect the environment is known as",
		"answer": "Eco-product Innovation"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The process of transitioning the management and ownership of a business to the next generation is known as",
		"answer": "Family Business Succession"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Partners who did not invest and is not eligible for profits but their names are used as partners are called",
		"answer": "Nominal partners"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The document that govern the internal management of the company's affairs, the duties, rights and powers of members is known as",
		"answer": "Articles of Association"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The combination of two companies to form a new and improved organization is called",
		"answer": "Merger"
	},
	{
		"question": "Who are referred to as Drone Entrepreneurs?",
		"answer":
			"They are old school entrepreneurs and are resistant to change. They prefer to stick to their traditional methods of production."
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A process of gathering information about a company's external events and relationships in order to assist with decision making at top managerial positiobs is called what ?",
		"answer": "Environmental Scanning"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The legal rights that safeguard creators and producers from copycats are known as what?",
		"answer": "Intellectual property"
	},
	{
		"question": "The two traditional branches of Intellectual property is ",
		"answer": "Industrial property and copyright"
	},
	{
		"question": "The Trademarks Act 1965 can be found in?",
		"answer": "Cap 436 Laws of the Federation of Nigeria (LFN) 1990"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The reproduction of a copyrighted work without the permission or any license from the author is called",
		"answer": "Infringement of a copyright"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The agency responsible for development of local raw materials for use by industries is known as what?",
		"answer": "RMRDC"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"The type of innovation whereby a new product which is an improved version of an existing product is produced is called",
		"answer": "Disruptive or Transformational Innovation"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"According to Schumpeter, entrepreneurship is what type of activity?",
		"answer": "creative"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A stage when more employees and income are expected to be made is known as",
		"answer": "The Growth Stage"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A partner that has the full power of participating in the conduct and management of the partnership business is called",
		"answer": "General partner"
	},
	{
		"question": "The CBN launched MSMEDF when and with a share capital of ",
		"answer": "August 15, 2013 with a share capital of N220 billion"
	},
	{
		"question": "NERFUND stands for what and was established when?",
		"answer":
			"National Economic Reconstruction Fund and it was established by FG in the year 1989 during Pres. Badamosi Babangida regime"
	},
	{
		"question": "The three activities involved in Entrepreneurship are: ",
		"answer": "identify opportunities, allocate resources and create value "
	},
	{
		"question": "Cantillon described an Entrepreneur as who?",
		"answer": "A risk-bearer and manager of firm"
	},
	{
		"question": "What are the types of business environments?",
		"answer": "Internal - Micro and External - Macro"
	},
	{
		"question": "PESTEL framework analyzes what type of business environment? ",
		"answer": "MACRO"
	},
	{
		"question": "The Copyright Act in Nigeria was derived from what convention?",
		"answer": "Berne Convention"
	},
	{
		"question": "NGOs are grouped into two using two focuses which are: ",
		"answer": "level of orientation and level of operation"
	},
	{
		"question": "Red Cross operates at what level of operation?",
		"answer": "National NGO"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"A form of business owned and managed by a single person is known as",
		"answer": "Sole Proprietorship"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Partners who do not participate in daily operations of the business are called",
		"answer": "Sleeping or Dormant partners"
	},
	{
		"question":
			"Wealthy individuals with high net worth who willing invest into businesses will less stringent conditions are called",
		"answer": "Angel investors"
	},
	{
		"question": "MSMEDF stands for what?",
		"answer": "Micro Small and Medium Enterprise Development Fund"
	}
]
}
